dsauerbrun@gmail.com - 818-254-8697

About me

Experienced application engineer with skillset ranging from managing infrastructure to front end development. Proficient in identifying solutions and bringing them from concept to execution. Delivered high-impact projects with measurable time and cost savings.

Languages

Typescript • Javascript • Go • Python • SQL • Ruby • HTML • CSS

Expertise

Angular • Automated testing • AWS • Bun • CI/CD • Concourse • Docker • ElasticSearch • Git • GraphQL • Kafka • Kubernetes • Node.js • NoSQL • Protocol Buffers • React • Redis • Ruby on Rails • Snowflake • Websockets

Experience

Opendoor - Remote

June 2022 - November 2024

Senior Software Engineer

Tech lead on the CRM team. Accountable for product roadmap planning, infrastructure, and CI/CD for business critical processes. Regularly met with product, design, operations, and adjacent engineering teams in order to fulfill these responsibilities.

- Crowning achievement was successfully replacing old and cumbersome tooling by designing a micro frontend framework in React. An initiative which had failed twice before.
- Decreased onboarding time for the Operations team by 30% by implementing previously mentioned framework.
- Scaled usage of modularized framework from 1 to 4 teams resulting in standardized internal tooling which reduced eng time for new initiatives by weeks. Growth achieved by collaborating with staff engineers on different teams and maintaining relevant documentation.
- Planned and implemented outreach service increasing top of funnel engagement by 5%
- Deprecated 3000+ lines of code in Rails codebase by moving business logic into Go microservices. Resulted in saving \$100k/year in cloud service costs.
- Eliminated 2 days/month of maintenance for infrastructure team by migrating two microservices off Kubernetes kOps cluster onto an EKS cluster.

BigBrain Games - Remote

June 2020 - April 2022

Senior Backend Engineer

Responsibilities included architecting backend system, ensuring performance by monitoring observability metrics, and managing Kubernetes cluster. Also volunteered to build BigBrain's CMS system from the ground up.

- Designed Node.js monolith to grow into microservices architecture. Emphasized performance by leveraging multiple layers of caches, ultimately serving up over 1000 requests per second.
- Reduced maintenance effort by setting up Knex.js. Migration rollbacks went from being an hour long dev effort to a simple few minutes.
- Reduced content quality error rates from 3/week to 1/week by replacing a spreadsheet based CMS with a homegrown CMS.

FulcrumPro - Remote

March 2017 - April 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

Developed an ERP application from ground up. Owned the solutioning for three different manufacturing clients. Wrote code across full stack, managed AWS(S3 buckets and RDS databases), and managed multiple linux servers.

- Achieved 20% annual revenue growth with 50% reduction in average workload for a Rubber extrusion company. Set up automated scheduling to gracefully handle failed jobs, a quoting system, and a calculation for raw material requirements which was surfaced to the manufacturing line.
- Improved throughput from 12 to 15 jobs per week for a laser perforation company by building automated QA system to alert line managers when job was trending out of tolerance. Alert would catch the problems before they arose reducing waste while ensuring jobs would finish on time.

Chatlingual - Boulder, CO

August 2015 - December 2016

Full Stack Software Developer

Migrated legacy .net system to Node.js. Built the backend, designed the data model for Postgres db, set up Redis cache, wrote websocket controller, built chat portal in Angularjs, and built lightweight chat widget in pure Javascript.

Freelance - Remote

October 2014 - August 2015

Software Developer

Contracted for travel startup to build signup funnel in Rails. Tracked users' origin and preferred destinations—alerting them of opportunities to book a private jet.

Novacoast - Santa Barbara, CA

August 2011 - September 2014

Software Development Consultant

Met with clients to gather requirements, write proposals, and implement solutions.

Education

UC Santa Barbara

September 2007 - June 2011

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science - College of Engineering

Connect

dsauerbrun.com • linkedin.com/in/dsauerbrun • github.com/dsauerbrun • climbcation.com